孩子们  你们还记得 我和罗宾的第一次约会...
Kids, you remember my first day with Robin.
- 我好像是爱上你了 - 什么?
- I think I'm in love with you. - What?!
可是正常人... 也就是不像你爸爸的人
Well, here's the thing, normal people, you know, people who aren't your dad,
一般晚一点才说出一句"我爱你"
usually take longer to say "I love you."
罗宾倒经过了正常的阶段...
Robin went through the usual stages.
- 蜘蛛!蜘蛛! - 我什么东西忘走廊里了
- Spider! Spider! - I left something in the hallway.
- 蜘蛛在哪? - 就在那
- Where? - Right there.
抓到啦
Got it.
刚开始你会想到你真的爱他
First there's the moment when you think you think it.
还没死
Whoa, still alive.
有一瞬间 你会认为你知道你爱他
There's the moment you think you know it.
你最好还是别亲我 你也会病的
Oh, you don't want to kiss me, you'll get sick.
完全值得
Totally worth it.
不久你会肯定你是爱他的 可是你不能告诉他
There's the moment where you know you know it,  but you can't yet say it.
现在太晚了  明天再聊
All right, it's getting to be that time. I'll talk to you tomorrow?
晚安
Good night.
泰德  等会儿
Wait, Ted?
什么事?
Yeah?
晚安
Good night.
行  那到时候见
Well, great, I'll see you then.
再见  甜心
Bye, sweetie.
泰德  你猜谁会来?
Hey. Guess what?
我妹妹凯蒂下周末来看我...
My sister Katie is coming to visit next weekend.
飞机星期四到
She gets in on Thursday.
太好了  你知道我有什么打算?
That's awesome. You know what I'm going to do?
我星期五请假不上班...
I'm going to take off work Friday.
我们带她到帝国大厦参观 (纽约有名建筑物)
We're gonna take her to the Empire State Building.
你真会这样做?
Really? You'd do that?
每个人都应该参观帝国大厦
Of course. Everyone should see the Empire State Building.
还有最后你知道你肯定爱上了他的时候...
And then there's the moment where you know you know it,
而且不能再不告诉他了
and you can't keep it in any longer.
- 泰德 - 什么?
- Ted. - Yeah?
肉丸 ("Falafel"是一种肉丸似的中东食品)
Falafel.
本字幕由YYeTs美剧字幕组原创翻译制作
仅供学习交流之用 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
欢迎访问YYeTs美剧论坛进行交流 www.YYETS.com
老爸老妈的浪漫史
第二季 第十二集
翻译：     Trip     校对：    雨亦奇
后期：     oliver0951      字幕监制：  叶煦
- 肉丸? - 肉丸
- Falafel? - Falafel.
你没跟泰德说"我爱你" 反而说了"肉丸"?
Instead of telling Ted you love him, you said "falafel"?
- 我说不出来 - 我就是不能理解...
- I totally choked. - I just don't get it.
为什么你不能告诉泰德你爱他?
Why can't you tell Ted you love him?
告诉一个人我爱他 对我来说是件很难的事
Oh, come on, this is a big deal for me.
你又不是从来没告诉过一个人你爱他
Oh, God, you'd think you never said it to a guy before.
不可能吧...
No.
听我解释  我一般 谈恋爱都没有到过这个阶段
Okay, well, I don't usually get this far in the relationship.
我一般恋爱都到 第三个星期就下高速公路了
I usually take the three-week exit.
你不会真的信巴尼的"高速公路"理论!
Don't tell me you're actually buying into Barney's freeway theory.
孩子们  好好听着 我要教你们一堂一生不忘的课
Watch your steps when you get up, kids, 'cause I am about to drop some knowledge.
谈恋爱就像一条高速公路
Relationships are like a freeway.
你上个月才告诉我 谈恋爱跟杂技团一样
Wait a minute, a month ago you told me relationships are like a traveling circus.
可是这个比喻是新的 胜过那个...
No, this is new. This trumps that.
高速公路和谈恋爱一样 都有出口...
Freeways have exits. So do relationships.
谈恋爱的第一个出口  是在谈到六个小时的时刻 我最爱的也是这个出口
The first exit, my personal favorite, is six hours in.
两人见面  交谈  做爱 然后在她洗澡的时候下高速
You meet, you talk, you have sex, you exit when she's in the shower.
每一个和你做爱过的女人 都立即要洗澡?
So every girl you have sex with feels the immediate need to shower?
其实不用回答  我理解
Actually, yeah, I get that.
接下来的三个出口是第四天  第三个星期 和第七个月...
The next exits are four days, three weeks, seven months--
你们俩到那时就会分手 日历上记着...
that's when you guys are gonna break up, mark your calendars.
什么?
What?
还有别的出口是一年半以后  十八年以后 和最后的出口  死的时候...
Then a year and a half, 18 years, and the last exit-- death.
如果你一生只跟一个女人在一起...
Which, if you've been with the same woman for your entire life,
你将会丧气地问到 "我们到了吗?"
it's like, "Are we there yet?"
我一辈子也没上过 这么长的高速公路...
So I've never been on the freeway this long before.
一般和一个人处了久以后 我就发现这个人的性格有毛病
I mean, usually by now I find out the guy has some weird personality thing
迫不及待的上下一个出口
that makes me want to take the next exit.
完全理解  这事对我也发生过
Yeah, been there.
我以前谈过一个只能 听着古典音乐方便的人...
I once dated a guy who could only go to the bathroom when classical music was playing.
这人是马修
Okay, it was Marshall.
我和泰德现在的感情这么好 我不想把它搞得更复杂
It's just things are going so well with Ted I just don't want to complicate it.
放心  到时候就可以克服这问题了...
Relax, it'll happen when it happens.
马修的古典音乐问题 也是这样解决的
Which is also the advice I gave Marshall to get him over the classical music thing.
凯蒂来了!
Oh, here comes Katie.
- 你妹妹真可爱 - 没错
- Aw, your sister's so cute. - Yeah.
现在让我回忆起来 以前送她回家的时候...
This reminds me of when I used to see her coming up the driveway from school,
扎得马尾辫子 背着她的凯蒂猫书包
with her little pigtails and her Hello Kitty backpack.
- 你好 凯蒂猫 - 糟糕了...
-  Hello, Kitty. - Oh, no.
不不不  不可能
No. No. No.
- 罗宾  过得好吗? - 哦  好  好
- Hey, Robin. How are you? - Oh, good. Good.
这个...长舌头的人是谁?
So, who is this... tongue person?
罗宾  这是我的男朋友凯尔
Robin, this is my boyfriend Kyle.
看起来你们家专出美女
Looks like hotness runs in the family.
谢谢了 你嘴真甜
Oh, you said that. Great.
你们交往多久了?
So how long have you two been...?
- 整整两个月 - 对
- Two whole months. - Yeah.
他其实也到纽约来看家人
He's actually coming to visit family in New York, too.
多完美?
Isn't that great?
我的一个表哥 23岁 混球一个 可是他给我买啤酒  所以...
My cousin. He's 23, kind of a wad, but he buys me beer, so...
那不错  这是我的朋友莉莉
That's cool. This is my friend Lily.
美女
Hot.
你小子嘴巴还真甜
You say things!
那我们回去吧  我帮你打理好
Well, come on, let's get you back to my place, we'll get you settled.
其实  今晚我和凯尔住
Um, actually, I'm going to stay with Kyle tonight.
- 不行  你今晚不会跟他住 - 求求你啦...
- Uh, no, you're not. - Oh, come on.
今晚是个特别的日子...
It's kind of a special night.
听懂了?
If you know what I mean.
什么?
What?
哦  哦...
Oh. Oh...
我不敢想相信 我的小妹妹会失身于一个
I can't believe my baby sister is planning to lose her virginity to a...
鸡冠头的猥琐男
...douche with a faux hawk.
这不能发生
This can't happen.
你们得帮我说服她
You guys have to help me talk her out of it.
告诉一个女人不要做爱
Speech to talk a girl out of having sex.
从来没干过
Yeah, I don't have any of those.
防止婚前性交 是有违我的宗教信仰的
Discouraging premarital sex is against my religion.
求你啦?我是她的大姐
Please? I'm her older sister.
我应该教她怎么做明智的决定
I'm supposed to teach her how to make good and responsible decisions.
已经两点了而且你已经 喝了三杯苏格兰威士忌了
It's 2:00 and you've already had three scotch and sodas.
正因如此 我才需要你们的帮忙
That's why I need your help.
第一晚  罗宾说服了她妹妹和她住
Robin convinced Katie to stay with her that first night.
第二天  我带大家去了帝国大厦
And the next day, I took everybody to the Empire State Building.
你们和一个建筑师来 太幸运了
You guys are lucky you came here with an architect.
帝国大厦趣事 第一
Empire State Building fun fact number one:
当1930年3月17号开始施工时...
When construction began on March 17, 1930,
这栋楼一个星期就建了四楼半
the framework rose at a rate of four and a half stories per week.
一个星期建四楼半
Four and a half stories per week.
这样的反应才差不多嘛
There it is. There it is. Come on.
这些不有趣吗 你们应该有点兴趣
These are fun facts, guys, let's have fun with them.
凯蒂  我一直都想来帝国大厦的...
You know, Katie, I have wanted to come to the Empire State Building for so long,
可是我一直在等着 和一个特别的人一起来
but I waited to come here with someone special.
又来了
Oh, here we go.
我和马修也没来过帝国大厦
Marshall and I have never been to the Empire State Building either.
可是我很高兴等了这么久 能和我的未婚夫一起干这么重要的事
But I'm so glad I waited to do something so important with my fianc?
说起等  我在高中 发过誓不要过早做爱
Speaking of waiting, I signed an abstinence pledge in high school.
等待也非常酷
It's totally cool to wait.
除了大麻以外  不要碰任何毒品
And stay away from drugs... other than pot.
- 你告诉他们了? - 是的  我告诉了他们
- You told them? - Oh, okay, yes, I told them.
我只想让你 听一听别的大人的意见
But only because I think you should hear it from other grownups, too.
他家都觉得你应该等  对不对?
Everyone thinks you should wait. Right, guys?
- 当然  你应该等 - 做爱很好玩
- Totally. You should wait. - Sex is fun.
看到了吗?
See?
你真虚伪 你16岁就失身了
You are such a hypocrite. You were only 16 when you lost yours.
你怎么的知道的?
Well, how do you know that?
你的日记忘在你的房间里了 也就是我的新房间
You left your diary in your old room slash my new room.
我花一万块钱买那本日记
I'll pay you $10,000 for that diary.
我已经和凯尔拍拖了两个月
Look, I've been dating Kyle for two months now.
久的快像是一生了
It's like forever.
我们别什么的都干过了
I  mean, we've already done everything else.
- 我们甚至连... - 哦 啦......
- I mean, we've even... - Oh. La, la, la, la, la.
啦...  啦...
La,  la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la.
连凯尔都能干那个
Even Kyle gets to do that.
你没资格阻止我
You have no right to tell me not to do it.
可是和凯尔? 为什么不能等?
But Kyle? Why can't you just wait?
如果等的话 你会遇见一个像泰德这么好的人
Because if you wait, you can get a nice guy like Ted.
罗宾  这会发生的
Robin, this is happening.
我已经发布在我的博客上了
Look, I already put it up on my Myspace page.
- 我要去抽一根 - 你现在也抽烟了?
- I need a clove. - You smoke now, too?
- 记得以前吗? - 不!
- Oh, remember cloves? - No!
不要说"记得以前吗?" 这不行
No "Aw, remember cloves?" This can't happen.
她还是我的妹妹  明白吗?
She's my baby sister, okay?
她应该在看"美人鱼" 喝果汁而不是跟凯尔鬼混
She should be watching The Little Mermaid and drinking Yoohoo, and not having sex.
可是你失去处女之身时也不就是16岁
Come on, you were only 16 when you had sex.
- 我当时17岁 - 我们是18岁的时候
- I was 17. - We were 18.
巴尼应该是12岁左右
Barney was probably 12.
泰德  玩笑开得好
Good one, Ted.
我当时是13...16...14...
I was, uh, six... fourt...
你当时多大?
How old were you again?
-伙计  我也是
- 17. - Dude, me, too.
- 巴尼  你没事吧? - 当然没有
- Barney, you okay? - Yeah, of course.
怎么  你不相信我?
What, you don't believe me?
- 我当时在夏令营  所以我... - 什么夏令营?
- It was at camp, so I'm... - What camp?
在郊外的一个地方  你拿地图找
This place in the Catskills. Look it up.
我那年在那教课
I was there teaching for the summer.
你教什么课?
What did you teach?
舞蹈
Uh, dance.
舞蹈?
Dance?
对泰德  舞蹈  也许你听说过...
Yeah, Ted, dance. Maybe you've heard of it.
原本只是一份简单的夏日工 结果变成了...
It was just a simple summer job, but it turned into so much more.
她的名字叫弗朗西斯 可是大家都叫她"宝贝"
Her name was Frances Houseman, but everyone called her Baby.
塞尔娃
# Sylvia #
米奇  什么事?
# Yes, Mickey? #
你管你的宝贝叫什么?
# How you call your loverboy? #
来这  宝贝
# Come here, loverboy #
如果他不回答
# And if he doesn't answer #
哦  宝贝
# Oh, loverboy #
如果他还是不回答?
# And if he still doesn't answer? #
我简单的说  宝贝儿
# I simply say, baby... #
宝贝
# Oh, baby #
我甜蜜的宝贝儿
# My sweet baby #
那是"风骚舞蹈" (电视节目)
That's Dirty Dancing.
- 昨晚电视上播了 - 不对 是两晚前
- It was on last night. - No, it was two nights ago.
"她像一阵风" 已经在我的脑海里 回荡了四十个小时了
"She's Like the Wind" has been stuck in my brain for about 40 hours.
我刚忘了  又想起了
I just got it out. Now it's back in.
该死的斯威泽 (Patrick Swayze热舞十七男主角演员)
Damn you, Swayze!
- 记得我们的第一次? - 记得
- Do you remember our first time? - Yeah.
是上大学的时候
It was back in college.
等一等
Oh, wait, wait.
我很想干这个  可是...
Look... I really want to do this, but...
你不觉得我们应该 把我们的第一次变得特别?
we should make it special, you know?
得干的到位
Do this right.
好
Okay.
我同意
You're right.
也许周末可以到海边租栋别墅
Maybe we could go to the beach and get a house for the weekend.
或者新年前夕
Yeah, New Year's Eve.
好
Okay.
我们还可以点一些蜡烛 放古典音乐
Oh, and we'll light candles and maybe put on some classical music.
我不喜欢那个主意
That's not a good idea.
为什么?
Why not?
很难解释
Long story.
可是我们可以听艾尔・格林的音乐 还可以一起泡澡
But maybe we could put on some Al Green and take a bubble bath together.
听起来是个好主意
Oh, yeah, that sounds so good.
我爱你  马修
Oh, I love you, Marshall.
我很高兴我们没那么性急
I'm so glad we're waiting.
12分钟后...
Oops.
- 那真可爱 - 告诉她接下来怎么了
- Oh, that's adorable. - Yeah, tell her what happened next.
- 那爽的不可思议 - 是呀
- That was amazing. - Yeah.
要再干一次?
Want to do it again?
求你们别了
Please don't.
- 我们道了谦 - 真的嘛  为什么又干了一次?
- We said we were sorry. - Yeah, well, then why'd you do it again?
我把我的随身听借给你了
You know what, I loaned you my Walkman.
反正意思是  不管怎么样 第一次都不会是想象得那么完美
The point is no matter what, it's never gonna be as perfect as you want it to be.
我的第一次非常糟糕
Well, mine was terrible.
等等  你还一直没告诉我过
Wait, I've never heard your story.
如你所知  我当时16岁
Well, as you know, I was 16.
是和我当时的男朋友 布莱恩  一起干的
And it was with my boyfriend Brian.
- 准备好了吗? - 好了
- Ready? - Yeah.
- 这气氛真好 - 我知道
- This feels so right. - Oh, I know.
- 罗宾 - 布莱恩
- Oh, Robin. - Oh, Brian.
对了  我是同性恋
Yeah, I'm gay.
- 我真为你感到痛苦 - 算了  我应该早就看出来了
- I'm so sorry. - Eh, I should've known.
有一些前兆
There were signs.
老天啊!
Oh, my God!
我妈回来了  赶快!
My mom's home. Quick!
- 躲到我床底下 - 什么?!
- Get under my bed. - What?!
老天啊!
Oh, my God!
你只有一个失去处女之身的机会
You only get one shot at losing your virginity.
虽然我只是干了一丁点 但也算...
And even though I just barely had sex, it counts.
What do you mean just barely?
比方说 他没跳到 游泳池的底下去  可是他...
Well, he didn't dive all the way into the pool, but he...
在浅的那一头玩了一下水
splashed around in the shallow end.
那样的话 他不算是你的第一次
Then you didn't lose your virginity to him.
- 一丁点不算 - 一丁点也算
- Just barely doesn't count. - Yes, it does.
- 不算 - 也算
- No, it doesn't. - Yes, it does.
不  不算 一丁点不算  争论解决了
No, it doesn't. It doesn't count. End of story.
莉莉  你这个小妖精
Ooh, why, Lily Aldrin, you saucy little harlot.
是不是在马修游泳之前 有别人试了水?
Could it be that before Marshall took a swim, someone else tested the water?
不  没有别人试过水  对吗?
No. Nobody else tested the water, right?
难道是史古特?
Scooter?
史古特是谁?
Who's Scooter?
我在高中的男朋友 我和他绝对没有过
My high school boyfriend, who I did not have sex with.
我...我不敢相信
I... I can't believe this.
我们可是马修和莉莉 别人看见我们会说
We're Marshall and Lily-- when people see us, they say,
"哦  看看他们 他们只跟对方上过床"
"Oh, look at them, they've only had sex with each other."
不  马修  人们其实说 "哦  看看他们"
No, Marshall, they say, "Oh, look at them,
他们只跟对方有过性交
they've only had sex with each other."
可是那不是真的了
But now that's not true anymore--
你上过床的人是我的两倍
now you've had sex with twice as many people as I have.
我一直就觉得 你在床上的技术太好了
I knew that you were too good at it.
知道吗? 我根本 不要看愚蠢的帝国大厦了
Know what? I don't want to see the stupid Empire State Building anymore.
- 帝国大厦不愚蠢 - 我要去看凯尔
- It's not stupid. - I'm going to see Kyle.
凯蒂  求求你了 你只有一个失去处女之身的机会
Katie, please. You only get to lose your virginity once.
你应该留给某个特别的人
You should only be having sex with someone who's special.
你跟一百多个人有了性交
Oh, please-- you've had sex with, like, a hundred guys.
没有一百个  没有一百个!
It's not a hundred guys. It's not a hundred guys.
我肯定你跟他们每一个都非常相爱
I'm sure you were madly in love with all of them.
我对每一个都有不同的感情...
I had different levels of feeling for each of the...
其实是个非常合理的数字
very  reasonable number of guys.
真的
Really.
那么  你爱泰德吗?
Well, do you love Ted?
你爱他吗?
Do you love Ted ?
我...
I, um...
帝国大厦趣事第二十二
Okay, Empire State Building fun fact number 22:
帝国大厦有很多 人们可以私下谈话的地方
The Empire State Building has tons of places where people can have private conversations.
- 你不用回答  好吗? - 就让我解释
- You're off the hook, okay? - Just let me explain.
你不用作任何解释 你不用说出来  没事
You don't have to explain anything. You don't have to say it-- it's fine.
好  可是如果谈恋爱 像条高速公路的话  那么...
Okay, but if relationships are like a freeway, then saying...
"嗯嗯嗯" 就像 进入共车道一样
"hm hm hm" is like... getting into the carpool lane.
而我不想下这道高速  可是...
And  I don't want to take an exit, but...
我还没有进入共车道的准备
at the same time, I'm not ready to get into the carpool lane.
知道在共车道里有什么吗?
Because what's in the carpool lane?
那有一颗大钻石 可是我还不愿意结...
Oh, it's a big diamond, and I'm just not ready to get...
好  罗宾  别说了
Okay, Robin, Robin, stop.
这没什么大惊小怪的 你不用说出来
It's no big deal-- you don't have to say it.
说出来是个大事 我不想说得太早
It's just, it's a big thing to say to someone, and I don't want to say it too soon.
怎么啦?你是说 像我说得那么早吗?
What, you mean like I did?
不  我没说...
No. I didn't...
对啊 你是有点早
Yeah, like you did.
可是  泰德  你也得承认 你那么早就说出来有点怪怪的
I mean, you have to admit it, Ted, it was a little weird.
- 奇怪...还是大胆? - 蛮奇怪是肯定的
- Weird... or courageous? - Pretty sure weird.
谁第一次约会就说出来?
I mean, who gives it up on the first date?
可是表现出我 勇敢得跟一个骑士一样
Well, come on, it shows I'm brave and bold, like a knight.
不  显示出你 是个爱说我爱你的浪子
No, it shows that you're an I-love-you slut.
那么你就是个 不说我爱你的吝啬鬼
Well, then you're an I-love-you prude.
算了  我把它收回来
You know what? I take mine back.
- 你...什么? - 我把我的"我爱你"收回来
- You... What? - I take my "I love you" back.
- 你不能说收就收 - 才不呢  我刚收回来了
- You can't take it back. - Nah. Just did. Got it right here.
既然我是个浪子 我干脆跟谁都说
But, you know, I'm such a slut, I'm just gonna give it away.
你  这位先生  我爱你
Hey, you, sir. I love you.
真得很感谢
Thank you, man.
我原本是要上楼跳下去的
I was going up there to jump.
马修  为什么你这么看重它
Marshall, why is this such a big deal?
为什么这么看重
Why is this such a big deal?
对不起 哥伦布 猜猜谁真的发现了北美洲?
Oh, uh, sorry, Christopher Columbus, guess who actually discovered the New World.
一个叫史古特的小子
Some dude named Scooter.
尼尔・阿姆斯特朗 其实是这样说的
Oh, uh, Neil Armstrong, it actually goes like this:
这是一个人的一小步 却是史古特的一大步
"One small step for man, one giant leap for Scooter."
亚当 猜猜谁在你之前...
Whoa, hey, Adam, guess who got with Eve
- 跟夏娃有了性交? - 好的  马修  我理解了
- before you did... - Okay, Marshall, I get it.
这之所以重要 因为我们的会因此历史而重写
It's a big deal because it rewrites our history.
不  不用
No, it doesn't.
这么说  你来过帝国大厦?
Look, have you been to the Empire State Building?
没有  你只来过第一楼的大厅
No. You've only been in the lobby.
人们买票的目的不是进入大厅
People don't buy tickets to get in the lobby.
买票的人都要到顶上去
They buy tickets to get to the top.
史古特只到过大厅 而大厅不算..
Scooter only got in the lobby, and the lobby doesn't count.
真的?
Really.
您能告诉我怎么到帝国大厦?
Excuse me, sir, uh, can you tell me how to get to the Empire State Building?
我们现在就在帝国大厦里面
Um, we're in it right now.
谢谢你  先生 你是个非常聪明的人
Thank you, sir. You're a very wise and brilliant man.
你没错
You're right.
我为什么要把一切都抛弃掉?
Why would I throw that all away?
今天真美好
I'm having the best day!
我得承认也许我没资格...
Katie, I'll admit, maybe I'm not in any place
在与感情有关的 问题上教训你  可是...
to lecture you on romantic relationships, but...
我真的不想 看到你跟我犯一样的错误
but I just don't want you to make the same mistakes that I've made.
- 相信我  凯尔不是同性恋 - 我说的不是那个意思
- Oh, believe me, Kyle is not gay. - That's not what I meant.
我只希望你没有这么急着长大
I just wish you weren't in such a rush to grow up.
求你不要和凯尔上床
Please don't do this.
可是  孩子们 凯蒂却和凯尔上了床
But, kids, later that night, Katie did it,
她怀了孕  生了四胞胎
and she got pregnant... with quintuplets...
余生住在一个破房子里
and she lived out her days in a trailer park...
死的时候还是个酒鬼
where she died an alcoholic.
孩子们  这个故事的寓意是 在结婚之前  决不能有性交
So the moral here, kids, don't have sex until you're married.
甚至  等到结了一两年婚以后
Maybe even, like, a year or two into marriage.
- 老爸! - 拜托 到底发生了什么?
- Dad! - Come on, what really happened?
好吧  说真的
All right, here's what really happened.
- Hey. - Hey.
她没有干
She didn't do it.
太好了!看来你说的话她听进去了
Hey, that's great! You got through to her.
我的话没进去  你的进了
No, I didn't. You did.
她告诉我 你和她谈了一会
She told me that you talked to her.
Hey, Katie.
Hey.
还有帝国大厦趣事要说?
Got another Empire State Building fun fact for me?
没了 我可不想 让你无聊的听我解释
No. I wouldn't bore you with the seven million man-hours
这幢102层的大楼是 如何在700万小时内建成
it took to build this 102-story testament to human will.
你没事吧?
So, you okay?
我不知道为什么 大家都大惊小怪的
I don't know what everyone is freaking out about.
凯尔是个很好的人
Kyle, he's a really nice guy.
他有机会和我的朋友葛蕾晨 在实验室胡搞 可是他没有
He could've cheated on me with my lab partner Gretchen Gwynn, but he didn't.
因为他说他知道我会发现
'Cause he said he knew I'd find out.
这听起来很坦率
That's very gallant.
我也不知道为什么 你姐姐把这事看得这么重
Well, I don't know what your sister's freaking out about, either.
- 我第一次的时候 跟你一样大 - 真的么?
- I was your age my first time. - Oh, really?
没错  是和这个叫莫利的女孩
Yeah, yeah. It was, uh, it was with this girl, Molly.
我爱你  泰德
I love you, Ted.
莫利  我也爱你
Oh, I love you, too, Molly.
可是我没有爱她
But I didn't.
那太爽了
That  was amazing.
对不起  我得走了
Look, I got to go.
你去哪?
Where are you going?
我的表哥从墨西哥搞了些爆竹
My cousin got some firecrackers from Mexico.
我们要去林子里点一些  很好玩
We're going out to the woods to light 'em-- it's gonna be awesome.
你会打电话给我吗?
Well, will you call me?
当然  我一定会打给你
Yeah. Yeah, I'll totally call you.
可是我一直没给她打电话
But I didn't.
莫利?
Molly?
什么?
Yeah?
可以借我二十块钱吗?我一定还
Can I borrow 20 bucks? I'll totally pay you back.
可是我没还
But I didn't.
我以后见都没见过她了
And I never saw her again.
我告诉她我爱她 可是...我只想要做爱
I told her I loved her, but... I just wanted to have sex.
我说什么都行 只要能和她鬼混
I-I would've said anything to make that happen, and...
而我就那么作了
that's exactly what I did.
我不想告诉你怎么做
Look, I'm not telling you what to do.
我只是想让你知道 十七岁的男孩是什么样的
I'm just telling you what all 17-year-old boys are like.
连"好人"也不例外
Even the nice ones.
我告诉凯尔我想等... 他就把我甩了
So I told Kyle I wanted to wait... and he dumped me.
我好抱歉
Oh, oh, sweetie, I'm so sorry.
甜心
Aw, honey.
我保证一切都会好起来的
I promise everything is gonna be okay.
你想不想看"美人鱼" 喝果汁?
You want to watch The Little Mermaid and drink some YooHoo?
你得在果汁里放一大勺糖
Only if you put a buttload of Kahlua in it.
别告诉妈妈
Don't tell Mom.
谢谢你
Thanks for doing that.
不用谢  我知道 对你来说这事意义很深
You're welcome. I knew it meant a lot to you.
你的故事里面的你一点都不像你
But, man, your story, I mean, it doesn't even sound like you.
嗯...
Yeah, well...
我爱你  茉莉
I love you, Molly.
泰德  我也爱你
Oh, I love you, too, Ted.
哇  刚才太棒了
Wow. That was amazing.
我的走了
Look, I got to go.
你-你要去哪?
Wh-Where are you going?
我的表哥从墨西哥搞了些爆竹
Uh, my cousin got some firecrackers from Mexico.
我们要去林子里点一些
We're going into the woods to light them.
肯定会非常好玩
It's gonna be awesome.
那么你会给我打电话?
Will you call me?
当然  我肯定会打电话给你
Yeah. I'll totally call you.
- 泰德? - 什么?
- Oh, Ted? - Yeah?
能借我二十块钱吗?我肯定会还给你
Can I borrow 20 bucks? I'll totally pay you back.
- 可是她没还. - 哦  过来
- But she didn't. - Oh, come here.
我爱你
I love you.
我说出来了
I said it.
感觉真好
Feels right.
- 我爱你 - 我是个同性恋
- I love you. - I'm gay.
开个玩笑
I'm kidding.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
你的"我爱你"处女说 没了
Hey... you lost your I-love-you-ginity.
嗯
Yeah.
我想我只是在等到个够格的男人吧
I guess I was just waiting for the right guy.
凯蒂最后在纽约玩得很开心
Katie ended up having a great first time in New York.
在她回家之前 我们以又去了一次帝国大厦
And the last thing we did before she left was go to the Empire State Building.
我很高兴我们终于一起来了
I am so glad we're finally doing this.
你说什么屁话呢? 我们昨天才来的这
What are you talking about? We were here yesterday.
是啊  可是那不算数
Yeah, but that didn't really count.
- 哦  惨了 - 对
- Oh, crap. - Exactly!
那么昨天我们不算来过这里
So yesterday doesn't count as having gone to the Empire State Building.
那么说马修你是我的第一次
So I lost it to you, Marshall.
而我乘那个电梯到了顶头...
And I rode that elevator to the top,
看到了美丽的风景 而我也沉醉其中
and I saw that view, and I basked in the awesomeness.
那才是我们的故事
And that's our story.
对  对  那是我们的故事
Yeah. Yeah, that's our story.
我们只跟对方做过爱
We've only had sex with each other.
他们只跟对方有过性交
They've only had sex with each other.
好了  大家一起进去
Ooh, okay, in, in we go, in we go.
有趣的帝国大厦事实第八十一点:
Okay, Empire State Building fun fact number 81:
从这里有１８６０个台阶...哇！哇！拜托
There are 1,860 steps from this... Whoa, whoa! Come on!
现在你们才能真正 说你们到过帝国大厦
So, now you guys can finally say you've been to the Empire State Building.
你们怎么在这住了 这么久却没来过顶上?
How have you lived here so long and never been to the top?
我们一般都很忙于...喝酒
Well, we're usually busy... drinking.
说到底一次  我们一直没听过...
Speaking of first times, we never got to hear
- 你是去处男之身的故事 - 对了  我差点忘了
- your virginity story. - That's right, I almost forgot.
我当时6岁  在棒球场上
Okay. I was 16, and it was in a baseball dugout...
＂里奇蒙高中的趣事＂ （一部青年电影）
Fast Times at Ridgemont High.
我是说  我和一个高档妓女一起在地铁里
I mean, I was in a subway with a high-priced call girl...
＂贸易冒险＂（另一部电影）
Risky Business.
我意外的在破入别人的电脑
I was accidentally hacking into NORAD'S computer...
那是＂战争游戏＂  里面都没有亲热的镜头
That's War Games, and there's not even a sex scene in it.
好啦！
All right!
我当时23岁  是和我妈妈的一个离婚了的朋友 她45岁  名叫隆达
I was 23, and it was with my mom's 45-year-old divorced friend, Rhonda.
她管我叫巴立叫了两个星期
She called me "Barry" the whole time, and for two weeks,
搞得我的床布满了 香烟的气味  你高兴了?
my comforter smelled like menthol cigarettes. You happy?
嘿...
Hey...
你还是告诉我们 你在夏令营的时候吧
Why don't you tell us again about your first time at the camp in the Catskills.
宝贝和她的家人 每年夏天都在那过
Baby and her family spent every summer at Kellerman's.
她爸爸不赞成我们相爱
Her dad did not approve of our love.
- 有人把宝贝搁在角落里吗? - 哦  天啊  没有
- Did anyone put Baby in a corner? - Oh, God, no.